Guide to the Rudolph Valuch Photograph Collection ALBA.PHOTO.142
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Rudolph Valuch Photographs
ca. 1937-1947
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Valuch, Rudolph
ALBA.PHOTO.142
0.5 Linear Feet (1 box)
Rudolph (Rudy) Valuch (1916[?]- ) was an apprentice tool and die maker affiliated with the Internatinal Association of Machinists. Valuch was attached to the 15th Transport Regiment of the International Brigades during the Spanish Civil War. The collection consists of photographic prints of the 15th Transport Regiment in Spain from April 1937 to September 1938 and contains group photographs and portraits of members of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade, Spanish troops, various military vehicles—motorcycles, tanks, trucks, planes—and street scenes.
Provenance
The Valuch Photographic Collection was donated to ALBA in 1989. The collection came to New York University in January 2001 as part of the original acquisition of ALBA collections.
Access Restrictions
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Tamiment Library & Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives for more information and to schedule an appointment, tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.
Historical/Biographical Note
Rudolph (Rudy) Valuch was an apprentice tool and die maker affiliated with the International Association of Machinists. At the time that he left for Spain in 1937 he was employed by the Illinois Tool Works. Valuch was attached the 15th Transport Regiment of the International Brigades during the Spanish Civil War and saw action at the Aragon front and the Battle of Brunete.
Valuch procured the majority of the images from the photographer Charles L. Kaufman. When the collection was donated to ALBA, Valuch provided a numbered inventory with captions that corresponded to 28 of the 111 prints. The collection is arranged in one series, alphabetically by topic. All of the photographs were taken in Spain.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of 111 photographic prints of the 15th Transport Regiment in Spain from April 1937 to September 1938 and contains group photographs and portraits of members of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade, Spanish troops, a variety military vehicles-motorcycles, tanks, trucks, planes-and street scenes.
Series I: The Rudy Valuch Photographic Collection contains 111 3 x 4 inch prints attributed to Charles Kaufman [from New York City?]. Most of the prints are of the 15th Transport Regiment, Spanish comrades who worked with the 15th Transport Regiment, and the location of operations of the Transport Regiment. The collection also includes portraits of Charles Kaufman, Morris Sennett, and David Thompson as well as photographs of Spanish street scenes, a downed Fascist plane, and buildings damaged by Fascist bombs and artillery shells. Many of these images were taken in Barcelona and Seville.
The photographic prints contain four numbers separated by colons. The first number refers to the collection number, the second to the box number, the third to the folder number, and the fourth to the individual print. For example, the first print in this collection is labeled 142:1:1:1.
Arrangement
Folders arranged alphabetically by topic.
The files are grouped into 1 series:
Missing Title
Prints
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
ALBA collections at the Tamiment Library.
Barcelona (Spain); Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939.; Black-and-white photographs.; Seville (Spain); Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Participation, American.; Valuch, Rudolph; Thompson, David, 1910-1989.; Spain. Ejercito Popular de la Republica. Abraham Lincoln Battalion; Sennett, Morris.
- Series I: Photographs
  - Armored Unit, ca.1937 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Artillery Crew: Group Portrait, ca.1937 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - At the Front: Materiel Caravan, ca.1937 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - At the Front: Non-Combat, ca.1937 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Ball, Homer Eugene and William James Jr., ca.1937 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Behind the Lines: Daily Life, ca.1937 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bombed/Shelled Buildings, ca.1937 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Downed Airplane, ca.1937 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Kaufman, Charlie: Portrait, ca.1937 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Lindfors, Veikko Oliver: Portrait, ca.1937 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Motorcycle Crew: Group and Solo Portraits (unidentified), ca.1937 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Partido Comunista de España: Headquarters, ca.1937 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Sennett, Morris: Portraits, ca.1937 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Spanish Troops: Casualties, ca.1937 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Spanish Troops: Daily Life, ca.1937 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Spanish Troops: Group Portraits (unidentified), ca.1937 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Spanish Troops: Recreation, ca.1937 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Spanish Troops: Solo Portraits (unidentified), ca.1937 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Spanish Women, ca.1937 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Squadron Members: Daily Life, ca.1937 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Squadron Members: Group Portraits, ca.1937 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Squadron Members: Solo Portraits (unidentified), ca.1937 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Street Scenes, ca.1937 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Truck Crew: Group Portraits (unidentified), ca.1937 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Thompson, David, ca.1937 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Valuch, Rudy, ca.1937 (Box 1, Folder 26)